Thomas Waldick

Front-End Software Engineer

Address: Columbus, USA
Planning to relocate to Germany
Email: contact@thomaswaldick.com
Nationality: German, American
Website: thomaswaldick.com

Date of birth: 02 June 1998 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/

Phone: +1 419 890 8274

thomas-waldick/ **Github**: github.com/
Thomaswaldick



Professional Profile

Front-End Developer with 6 years of experience specialized in **Javascript**. Developed a responsive web application in a dynamic startup environment, focusing on user interface design, cross-browser compatibility, and performance optimization.

Eager to bring my experience in front-end Javascript frameworks and dynamic work environments to your company, and contribute to its missions.

Primary stack: Vue.js, Typescript, Next.js, React.js, React Native, NoSQL (Firestore)

Work History

06/2018 - present

Lead Software Engineer

Weight Room Coach - weightroomcoach.com | Chillicothe, USA (Remote) Software for schools to create wellness programs and strength training for coaches, athletes, administrators, and staff.

Tech stack: Vue.js, React Native, Nuxt.js, Firebase, Heroku

- Scaled our customer base from 0 to 38 school districts by developing a new Vue.js website and React Native mobile app.
- Engineered a system supporting ~4000 athletes using Cypress E2E testing, clean and modular code.
- Facilitated a 200% increase to student-athletes baseline strength through customized workouts and programs.
- Established an Agile workflow using Github Actions, Trello, and Heroku.

05/2019 – 08/2019

Software Engineering Intern

Quicken Loans - quickenloans.com | Detroit, USA An online mortgage lender, offering home loans and refinancing solutions. **Tech stack**: .NET, C#, Angular, AWS, SQL

- Participated in a quarter which brought in \$32 billion in mortgage volume.
- Debugged numerous bugs in an existing code base through .NET and C#.
- Developed custom internal AWS developer tools using Angular.
- Assisted in resolving tech issues through a SAFe workflow practices.

05/2018 - 12/2018

Student Software Engineer

Ohio University - ohio.edu | Athens, USA

The Office of Information Technology creates software for the university. **Tech stack**: Angular, Ansible, Groovy, Grails, Java, NodeJS

- Automated CI/CD processes using languages like Ansible and Groovy.
- Engineered website features for students and faculty through Angular and Grails.
- Participated in an Agile work environment to complete code sprints using tools including Jira and Bamboo.

08/2017 - 05/2018

Help Desk Technician

Ohio University (Bobcat Depot) - ohio.edu | Athens, USA The Bobcat Depot is Ohio University's campus store with a tech help desk. **Tech stack**: Footprints Ticketing System, Office 365, Windows, Mac

- Helped 100+ students and faculty with their tech issues by applying expertise and collaborating with colleagues.
- Facilitated support for numerous customers while documenting the process using Footprints ticketing system.

Education

08/2017 – 05/2021

Bachelor in Computer Science

Ohio University Athens, USA

Additional Skills & Interests

Languages

• English (Mother Tongue), German (Basic)

Interests

- I love playing board games to connect with friends and unwind offline.
- I enjoy watching Youtube and Twitch streamers while working on coding side projects.